[Music]
this is a quick update about a big event
we've got coming up next Sunday
and also a quick update as to what we're
doing and how we're trying to kind of
ramp up rebel wisdom to respond to
what's going on because our sense is
that this is a beginning of as Jordan
Hall talks about the meta-crisis a lot
of these sort of systemic issues that
we've talked about on the channel around
existential risk and phase-shift are now
really kind of coming home to roost like
this is where we feel that we're at we
feel that this is going to be just the
first stage in a growing crisis that is
going to be who knows how long it will
last but it but it will be part of this
sort of shift into a new operating
system as the old operating system shows
that it's not really fit for purpose and
we're going to try and kind of outline
that in the films we're gonna be putting
out over the next week's but we're also
thinking because we've always been about
not just the intellectual content but
also about kind of the the inner shifts
that we need to kind of make to be equal
to the challenge of the times that's
what we're really thinking about with
this big online event which Ali's going
to talk about now yeah so the event is a
free online event it's gonna be on
Sunday April the fifth and it's really a
combination of the two things we have in
the title resilience and sense making so
the part of the way it came about is we
were we were talking about what what's
really needed right now what are we all
in need of and those qualities feel
really essential in a time when there's
a huge amount of change a huge amount of
complexity so resilience is our ability
to withstand pressure and that's
becoming more and more important and
since making it is obviously our ability
to understand what's going on and those
two concepts and those two qualities
that we can develop are very tightly
coupled together because if we can't
make sense of the world and we don't
know what's going on we don't know which
way to turn you don't know which
direction to go in that has a huge
impact our resilience kind of wears it
down so we need to be connecting both of
those things together so in this film
we'll kind
introduce you to who's gonna be at the
event and they kind of split in two
let's call them sense makers so people
like Jamie wheel and Dinah Shore
Hamilton who will talk about the moment
and then a whole host of amazing
facilitators who we've we know where
we've worked with in the past to who can
really give tools that that increase
either our resilience or our sense
making so here we're just gonna play a
few short clips from some of the
speakers and facilitators who are going
to be taking part in the event starting
with Jamie wheel things are likely to
destabilize before they Rico here I
think I opened our talk on Thursday
night with this same quote from
Buckminster Fuller because it's it gets
us to the point where he says quite
clearly our task is predominantly
metaphysical but is how to get all of
humanity to educate itself swiftly
enough to generate spontaneous social
behaviors that will avoid extinction now
he read that half a century ago sure he
was on time there were many many things
he was well ahead of the curve on so we
also have Diane musho Hamilton who we've
had on the channel before and Diane is a
really an expert facilitator she's a Zen
master and has a lot of experience in
mediation as well so Diane is gonna be
helping us to make sense of the
emotional landscape we find ourselves in
right now so I find that the two
together are extremely helpful and
during our time right now where we're
experiencing more global stress we talk
about existential threats and wicked
problems right now we're experiencing
this challenge of this virus that's
affecting all public health around the
world it's really important that we but
we have both skill sets so then we've
got a combination of sort of individual
practices for resilience and also
community resilience how do we build
more anti fragile community for
ourselves where we live and also online
so we have Sarah ness and rich Bartlett
who we both featured recently in our
film about resilience I think it's
really important what they're going to
share are things really really important
and we're also going to create a space
for people to offer help and also ask
for help and
try and create more of a kind of
community feeling of everyone who's
attending the event so as well as the
talks and the framing then we have a lot
of different practices and the practices
are really important we've said on the
channel quite a few times that we you
know we need an intellectual framing we
need to be able to make sense of things
but then we need to really live these
insights out in our own lives and that's
where we see the real impact is when we
combine those two things and so and as
well as that we we're really conscious
of having I think John for baekje often
calls an ecology of practices so lots of
different techniques and practices
trained different skills and different
types of awareness in us and so we're
trying to get as broad a range as we can
so for example we have breath work and
breath work is really really really very
effective at helping us to gain insight
but also to regulate our nervous systems
it's a control of our nervous system and
build our resilience consciously so we
have amazing breath work facilitator
called Nicola price who's going to be
leading some breath work sessions and we
also have various different types of
movement or what we sometimes call
embodiments are really coming into an
awareness of our bodies and really
connecting to that so we have coral for
who's a brilliant yoga master we've
worked with before as well and we have
Chris crude le who is a martial arts
expert and so a TV presenter so he'll be
giving some simple techniques people can
use as well and we also have a variety
of other practices from from mindfulness
and relating practices as well so
there'll be a lot on offer and people
can kind of in those sessions pick and
choose whatever it feels like you need
the most right now there should
hopefully be something for you so yeah
on that note as well about relational
practices we're also releasing a couple
of films that we made for our online
course one about inquiry and one
meditation that we recorded around in a
sovereignty and the inquiry one is
basically a guide to how to do inquiry
is something we've talked about in the
past on the channel we talked about
circling and different forms of dialogue
of pursuing the truth of the moment like
it's a really really important practice
and the inquiry film talks about how to
develop
a practice of inquiry and why I think
that's really important that it'll go
through in a lot more detail but what it
really amounts to is a relational
practice it's like a talking meditation
of really trying to kind of come to the
truth of what wants to emerge in the
moment and why I think that's really
really important especially right now is
that as we start to develop that as a
practice we start becoming much more
aware of that in ourselves much more
self-aware and then we also start to
notice in the outside world what is new
and exciting and what is emergent in in
the culture we start to attune ourselves
to what wants what is much more emergent
in the culture and that's really
important right now because I think
we're very clear that all of the
pre-existing fixed answers and
ideologies are not going to be enough
for the task we're going to have to kind
of go into the liminal we're in the
liminal right now I'm going to have to
go deeper into it to come out the other
side so that's what these practices
allow us to do yeah that's a really nice
point about the liminal because part of
that that kind of in-between space that
we're in as a culture and I think a lot
of us feel we're in in our lives right
now because of the environment you know
one of the skills that really helps in
that moment is the ability to be present
and the ability to be with whatever's
going on and to kind of flow with it and
that's very much what part of what
inquiry can give is that we're on a kind
of flowing process of following
different threads as they emerge rather
than trying to place a frame onto
something and so the other thing we're
releasing that we've had from that we
developed rather for the online course
is what we call the sovereignty
meditation and the sovereignty
meditation combines a lot of the
practices we've mentioned already so it
combines breadth and then goes into
concentration source or meditation so
really zooming in and then goes into
contemplation and mindfulness zooming
out and then into inquiry either
journaling or inquiring with someone and
actually in a way the structure of that
meditation kind of says something as
well about
partly what's needed and partly why
we're doing this this day is that
there's a combination in that of zooming
in and zooming out so Joan rebecky says
really you know talks really well about
the fact that some practices help us
really zoom in and get more insight into
ourselves but we also need to combine
that with zooming out
so that kind of seeing the bigger
picture was when we zoom out we can see
where our frames are broken and a lot of
these practices are about very much like
removing your glasses saying okay where
where have we been seeing things
incorrectly where have we been deceiving
ourselves in some way and that's in a
way what we're doing as an entire
culture right now you know business as
usual is is gone and I would say
probably never coming back
and so we're left now with to some
degree other fixing or creating new
frames like new ways of seeing the world
new ways of interacting and it's crucial
that we have some kind of process of
thinking deeply about this and you know
talking about it but then these
practices keep it fresh and they keep us
from falling into different cognitive
traps that we all have capacity to fall
into so in in a sense it's about the
development of wisdom individually and
as a group yeah and the other thing that
we are starting to really ramp up is the
community calls we were doing there
every month and we're now going to be
doing them every week and with a guest
so the next one next fuse day will be
with Jordan Hall so a group sense-making
call with Jordan Hall which you
mentioned at the beginning Allie but
it's for me sense making is an
absolutely essential part of resilience
because if we can really understand and
Jordan Hall is one of the best of that
kind of just explaining what the deeper
shifts are that we're seeing and the
decay of kind of our own systems what
wants to come through if we can really
understand that then we're not gonna we
are going to be more resilient cuz we're
not gonna be surprised by what happens
we're gonna basically I think a lot of
people who've been watching us walked in
the channel for a long time
certainly from the sense-making calls
that we've had so far most of them have
said we were expecting this we we feel
like we knew this was going to happen
and we feel actually quite excited about
what the shift is that we're on the
verge on so if you can really understand
what these deeper shifts are we can
prepare and we can not be knocked off
our sense of when they happen yeah so
just to just a round off if you're
interested in taking part in the day
then do register there'll be a link in
the show notes below and we'll see you
soon as the tech revolution continues to
destroy old media the Internet is
fueling a new intellectual awakening
television made people look stupider
than they were it turns out that people
are smarter with longer attention spans
then we thought I'm a journalist and
filmmaker for many years I made
documentaries for the likes of the BBC
and channel 4 but I don't think the
mainstream media can provide the level
of analysis and insight we need for the
extraordinary times we're going through
where the old structures that made sense
of the world break down it's like we're
entering just entering into the
underworld and it's a descent we're
feeling everything starting to shake and
the center cannot hold
and when our ways of thinking break down
it's the rebels and the renegades who
dare to think differently who are needed
to reboot the system all right so what's
happening is that people are perceiving
because it's becoming increasingly
obvious that all of these artifacts of
the way that we've gone about doing
civilisation are breaking down and
failing in a way that is no longer easy
to pretend isn't happening and so as a
consequence this triggers a deep
visceral sense and that's a good thing
right because that deep visceral sense
is the return to the aluminum the return
to the mystery the shift that we are on
the precipice of is not like the shift
from the Dark Ages to the Enlightenment
it's like more like a shift from single
cell to multicellular life
these are the people and ideas rebel
wisdom is searching out to try to make
sense of the growing chaos the evolution
screwed up it handed us the tools to
recognize that we don't have to value
the game that it is playing and that we
can now repurpose the hardware to
something that's actually worthwhile
that's what I actually have hope in is
that if if enough people can come to
that realization then then we wake up
and not in some
evangelical megachurch kind of way of
being born again but in in a truly
initiatory way being born again of like
I know my purpose I know my part and I'm
willing to practice resurrection I'm
willing to offer my life fully and
freely in love in every moment and then
we're invincible like then we can turn
things on a dime it's also about trying
to create a new form of conversation one
base on genuine dialogue letting go of
ideology and fixed ideas so we want to
be a place that hosts this new form of
conversation both online and at our
events check out our films join the
conversation and to get early access to
some great films and exclusive content
please consider supporting us on patreon
you